Epoxy Art Group Archive 1982-1992 MSS 367
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
Epoxy Art Group Archive
1982-1992
MSS 367
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
0.5 linear feet (3 document cases, 1 binder, 1 flat box, and 1 oversized box)
Epoxy was an art collective that specialized in collaborative, multi-media, and experimental projects. Active between the years of 1982 and c. 1988, Epoxy's membership consisted of New York City based artists originally from Hong Kong. Files include original artwork, photographs, slides, press releases, press coverage, some business files and correspondence, and internal meeting minutes as well as other writings.
Fay, Ming
Biographical/Historical note
Epoxy was founded in 1982 by Ming Fay, Jerry Kwan, Kwok, Bing Lee, Kang Lok Chung, and Eric Chan— six New York City based viual artists with cultural ties to Hong Kong. The name "Epoxy" is a reference to epoxy resin. This name was selected by the collective in order to, in their own words, "represent the strong bonding power of good adheasiveness." Epoxy art group specialized in experimental, collaborative, and mixed media work. Slide show presentations and newspaper collages were perhaps the most commonly utilized meduims among their diverse artistic output.
Between the years of 1982 until circa 1992, the group held routine meetings and mounted exhibits approximately twice a year in a range of venues, including Kwok Gallery, the Sabrina Fung Gallery, the Alternative Gallery, and the New Museum. Epoxy's exhibitions as well as their less conventional projects and public art works include Works on the Wall (1983), Ball Show (1983), Pink Works (1984), Erotica (1984), Myths (1985), Roots of Reality (1985), Dragon, Eagle, Apple, and Pear (an outdoor art show at the Red Spot, 1986-7), Out of Context (1987), 36 Tactics (1988), 18 Layers of Hell (1988), and a public art exhibit in conjunction with REPOhistory (1990-1992).
Scope and Content
This collection documents Epoxy Art Group from its founding in 1982 until the group disbanded circa 1992. Files include original artwork, photocopies of artwork, photographs, slides, press releases, press coverage, some business files and correspondence, and internal meeting minutes and other writing. This material has been divided into three series.
Series I: Exhibition Files: These files document Epoxy's exhibitions as well as less conventional projects and public art works between the years of 1983-1992.
Series II: Administrative Files: This series is divided into three subseries.The first series contains a a range of material, including articles, press releases, photographs, artwork, and more. The second series consists of material that was removed from a blue green binder and rehoused in an archival binder. It includes press releases and photographs of Epoxy members. Finally, the third series contains three stamps and two stamp pads.
Subseries A: Files
Subseries B: Photo binder
Subseries C: Objects
Series III: Media Epoxy Art Group Record's includes one cassette tape, which has been separated as its own series primarily for preservation reasons.
Arrangement
Series I is organized chronologically by date of exhibit. Files in Series II: A are originized alphabetically. Original order was preserved in Series II: B (the photo binder).
Provenance
Epoxy's records were stored at the private residence of Ming Fay, a founding member of Epoxy. They were transferred to the Asian/Pacific/American Institute (APA) at NYU and then to Fales Special Collection and Library in 2013.
Related Archival Materials note
REPOhistory Archive
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Chan, Eric, (artist); Chung, Kang Lok; Fay, Ming; Kwan, Jerry; Kwok, Mang Ho; Lee, Bing, (artist); Art and society.; Art |v Exhibitions.; Artistic collaboration; Asian American art |y 20th century |v Exhibitions.; Asian American artists |z New York (State) |z New York |v Societies.; Asian American artists.; Asian Americans |x Ethnic identity.; Clippings (information artifacts); Collages (visual works).; Color slides.; Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Financial records.; Multimedia (Art); Photocopies.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Printed ephemera.; Race |x Political aspects.
- Series I: Exhibition Files
  Scope and Content
  These files document Epoxy's exhibitions as well as less conventional projects and public art works between the years of 1983-1992.
  - Works on Wall, February 8-11 1983 [1 of 3], 19883 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Works on Wall, February 8-12 1983 [2 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Works on Wall, February 8-12 1983 [3 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Works on Wall, February 8-11 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Works on Wall Portfolio Copies [Folder Removed from Works on Wall, Feb 8-12 1983] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Works on Wall [Booklets], 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ball Show, May 3 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ball Show Portfolio Copies [Folder Removed from Ball Show May 5 1983] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Pink Works" May 25 1984 [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Pink Works" May 25 1984 [2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Pink Works" Portfolio Copies [Folder Removed from "Pink Works" May 25 1984] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Pink Works [Slide Show], [1984] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Erotica" September 11-29 1984 [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Erotica" September 11-29 1984 [2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Erotica" September 11-29 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Erotica Portfolio Copies [Folder Removed from Erotica September 11-29 1984] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Erotica Portfolio Copies [Folder Removed from "Erotica" September 11-29 1984] (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Slides [from Erotica], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Epoxy Erotica [Slides], [1984] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Erotica Shoe [Slide] Show [1 of 2], [1984] (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Erotica Shoe [Slide] Show [2 of 2], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - [Flyers from Pink Works and Erotica Exhibit], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Myths" June 7-28 1985 [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Myths" June 7-28 1985 [2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Roots to Reality" Oct 11-Nov 24 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dragon, Eagle, Apple, and Pear: Outdoor Art Show Red Spot, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Out of Context 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Out of Context- Exhibition, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - [Material from 36 Tactics], [1988] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - [Material from 36 tactics], [1988] (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 36 Tactics [1 of 2], 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 36 Tactics [2 of 2], 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Originals [Chinese Writing of folder-Thrity Six Tactics Project] [1 of 4], [1988] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Originals [Chinese Writing on folder- Thirty Six Tactics Project] [2 of 4], [1988] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Originals [Chinese writing on folder- Thirty Six Tactics Project] [3 of 4], [1988] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Originals [Chinese writing on folders- Thirty Six Tactics Project] [4 of 4], [1988] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 36 Tactics Artwork, [1988] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 36 Tactics Artwork [1 of 7], [1988] (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 36 Tactics Artwork [2 of 7], [1988] (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 36 Tactics Artwork [3 of 7], [1988] (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 36 Tactics Artwork [4 of 7], [1988] (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 36 Tactics Artwork [5 of 7], [1988] (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 36 Tactics Artwork [6 of 7], [1988] (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 36 Tactics Artwork [7 of 7], [1988] (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Epoxy 36 Tactics [Slide Show], [1988] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 18 Levels of Hell, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Epoxy 18 levels of Hell [Slideshow], [1988] (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - ReproHistory, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series II: Administrative and Organizational Records
  This series is divided into three subseries.The first series contains a a range of material, including articles, press releases, photographs, artwork, and more. The second series consists of material that was removed from a blue green binder and rehoused in an archival binder. It includes press releases and photographs of Epoxy members. Finally, the third series contains three stamps and two stamp pads.
  - Subseries A:
    - 1997- Epoxy [Folder Removed from Epoxy: Bio-Material] [1 of 2], 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1997- Epoxy [Folder Removed from Epoxy: Bio-Material] [2 of 2], 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Art Mail [one flyer], undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - [Correspondence, Mock Ups, etc.], 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - [Correspondence, Mock Ups, etc.], 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Epoxy Artists, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Epoxy: Bio-Material, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Epoxy: Bio- Material, 1987-1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Epoxy Memo [1 of 3], 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Epoxy Memo [2 of 3], 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Epoxy Memo [3 of 3], 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Epoxy Slide Show, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Epoxy [writing in Chinese- from Art Project], undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Flyers and Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - [Large photographs of Epoxy members in masks, logos, etc.], undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - [Large Photographs of Epoxy Members in Art Masks, logos, etc], undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Ledger [Business Records] [1 of 2], 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Ledger [Business Records] [2 of 2], 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - [Loose Material Removed from Blue Green Binder], undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Ming Fay [Slide Show] Epoxy Hammer 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - [Out on their Ears Poster], undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - [Packet from San Francisco Art Institute], 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - [Photocopies of Press Releases and Art], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - [Photographs of Epoxy Members in Art Masks], undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - [Photographs of Collective and Negatives from their art] [1 of 3], undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - [Photographs of Collective and Negatives from their Work] [2 of 3], undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - [Photogtaphs of Collective and Negatives from their work] [3 of 3], undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - [Small Drawings] [1 of 3], undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - [Small Drawings] [2 of 3], undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - [Small Drawings] [3 of 3], undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - [Untitled Slide Show], undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Wu Lu Man (Epoxy) [Slide Show], undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Subseries B: Photo Binder [organizational material and photos removed from blue green binder] (Box 4)
  - Subseries C: Objects
    - Small Epoxy Stamp (Box 5, Object ID: 367.2.0001)
    - "Epoxy Art Group P.O. B 879; Canal St. Sta. NY, NY 10013" stamp (Box 5, Object ID: 367.2.0002)
    - Larger Epoxy Stamp (Box 5, Object ID: 367.2.0003)
    - Trodat printy stamp pad (Box 5, Object ID: 367.2.0004)
    - Kwik Stamp II pad (Box 5, Object ID: 567.2.0005)
- Series III: Media
  Epoxy Art Group Records' includes one cassette tape, which has been separated into its own series primarily for preservation reasons.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries A: Audio
    - 1983 Chinese Artists in NYC at Hammer Quist Gallery (Box 5, Media ID: 367.0001)